## **Jimmy Tidey**

I bring technical skills and academic rigour to user experience research and service design.

I love bridging across cultures and specialisms; my diverse background has helped me make unique contributions in a range of contexts - from start-ups to Google to public policy.



### **Employment**

#### Google

User Experience Researcher

2021 - 2023

Secondments to two UXR teams, ~ 40% commitment over 18 months.

- Implemented a new feature on an internal tool used by ~3000 engineers by planning and executing a mixed-methods research project, including:
  - o **In-depth interviews** screening, moderation and analysis.
  - Concept testing using Figma to create prototype UIs for user testing.
  - Data analysis & visualisation using SQL/Python to analyse how many users would be affected by the proposed new feature.
- I built a case for adding a new feature to Environmental Insights Explorer, a tool to help cities reduce their carbon footprint. I conducted a **literature and policy review**, leading to a new feature being added to the product roadmap.

#### Google

Business Program Manager, Brand Studio

2018 - 2023

As a BPgM I built and scaled tools and workflows to help keep Google marketing creative, efficient and secure. I received a promotion. My work included:

- Service design e.g. leading a project to build a tool that unified all the reviews
  required for launching a marketing website, now used by thousands of projects
  globally. As a BPgM, I ran workshops, undertook service mapping and
  implemented user satisfaction metrics. I authored policies and design guides. My
  projects focused on simplifying user journeys and required deep collaboration
  between engineering, legal, security and privacy teams.
- Tech project management overseeing web dev projects, including using agile project management; reviewing technical design docs; advising on security issues; negotiating access to datasets.

# Royal College of Art Practice-based PhD i

Practice-based PhD in design research

2013 - 2019

I built and evaluated *LocalNets*, a Twitter analytics mapping & visualisation tool for the public sector. LocalNets was tested in context, including with the NHS and a central government department. Three partners paid a monthly subscription to continue using LocalNets after our research projects completed.

- **Delivering paid-for software** iteratively developed through a design research framework, including focus groups & interviews. My thesis drew on my practical work to suggest design principles for social media analytics.
- Technical skills I built LocalNets, including front-end web development, using machine learning tools and implementing network analysis algorithms.

#### **Education & Skills**

# Selected training & skills

- Building prototypes using HTML/CSS/React
- Data analysis (Python / Colab, MySQL, BigQuery)
- Range of technical Machine Learning courses
- BSc Physics and Philosophy, University of Bristol (2:1)
- Writing for business, policy, academic and user-facing settings